<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Reid Sata</title>
		<description>Some writing among other things.</description>
		<link>http://example.org</link>
		<atom:link href="http://example.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Japanese Chefs in Paris</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I had the chance to eat at a little restaurant in Paris call Le Sot L’y Laisse.  We later learned on the way home that Le Sot L’y Laisse is a small piece of dark meat located on the back, and considered the best part of the chicken.  Cool.  Anyways, the restaurant serves French food, and is run by a Japanese chef.  I had fois gras and fish.  Each was perfectly prepared, and aranged on the plate like a piece of art.  Oh and also the absolute best tasting food I have ever eaten.  Both dishes were French, but as you might expect, had a lot of Japanese influence.  This was the second time I’ve gone to a French restaurant here run by a Japanese chef.  I thought it was pretty interesting because it’s not often you see Japanese chefs cooking non-japanese food in Paris.  Or so I thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About a week after that, I got to go to this fancy shmancy place called OKA.  It’s a little place that fits about 20 people jam-packed.  The cool thing here is that you have no idea what the chef is cooking that day.  When you enter, the only clue you get is the list of ingredients (for alergies).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, one week after eating at the best place I’ve ever eaten at ever, I ate at another place that is now the best place I’ve ever eaten at ever.  We had 6 courses that included included everything from ice cream in the entree, to perfectly prepared fish, to beef that melts in your mouth, to things I don’t even know how to describe. The point is it was all delicious, and tastier than anything you could ever imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this place as well, the chef was French, but the dishes definitely had some japanese influence in the ingredients and presentation.  I looked into it a little further and it turns out Japanese chefs have had a pretty strong presence in the French cooking scene for the last decade or so, serving as apprentices at many of the popular, hip, modern restaurants around Paris.  Now, they’re opening their own places, taking traditional French dishes and adding their own flare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few articles and pictures:
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tmagazine.blogs.nytimes.com/2014/12/12/japanese-french-cuisine-nakatani-restaurant-pages/?ref=tmagazine&quot;&gt;NYT Blog&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.travelandleisure.com/articles/japanese-chefs-heat-up-the-paris-restaurant-scene&quot;&gt;Travel + Leisure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/lesotlylaisse.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Le Sot L&#39;y Laisse Fish&quot; class=&quot;food&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/oka-entree.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;OKA entree&quot; class=&quot;food&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/oka-fish.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;OKA fish&quot; class=&quot;food&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/oka-dessert.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;OKA dessert&quot; class=&quot;food&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://example.org/blog/posts/japenese-influence-in-parisian-food/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://example.org/blog/posts/japenese-influence-in-parisian-food/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Playing Around in Meteor.js</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Last summer, I taught myself a little HTML and CSS.  Over the past year, one hour of procrastination lead to another, I learned a little JS, a few libraries and frameworks, and now I can build basic web apps.  I’ve never taken a formal programming class, so I’m sure my code is full of things that would make any experienced developer cringe.  But it works, and so they tell me, that’s all that matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, the most difficult part for me has been learning backend development.  Something just doesn’t quite click for me and I much prefer spending time on the frontend thinking about look, feel, and UX.  So I was pretty stoked when I found Meteor a couple months ago.  No more hours digging through StackOverflow and blog tutorials figuring out how to set up a database, create secure logins, connect oauth, bla bla bla&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So anyways, the past couple weekends I’ve been throwing together a simple contacts app.  Yes, it’s been done before, but I needed a way to manage some contacts so I figured I’d learn a little and make one myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With one year left of college, I’ve started reaching out to various connections and people whose work I admire and find interesting.  I guess adults call this networking.  I keep the list of people to contact in a note on my phone, but as the list gets longer, it’s more difficult to keep track of where everybody lives, what their emails are, etc.  I wanted a way to make sure that when I get back to the US, I know who I need to contact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so here’s the contacts manager I made.  I might add a couple features in my free time/fix the issues with it, but for now, it’s simple and it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Github: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rsata/contacts-manager&quot;&gt;https://github.com/rsata/contacts-manager&lt;/a&gt;
Demo: &lt;a href=&quot;http://simple-contacts-manager.meteor.com/&quot;&gt;http://simple-contacts-manager.meteor.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://example.org/blog/posts/contacts-meteor-fun/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://example.org/blog/posts/contacts-meteor-fun/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Mobile Money Potential</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Centralized payment processing companies like Visa or MasterCard exist so that we can open accounts with whatever bank we want, but still pay on the same machines.  If they didn’t, each bank would need its own payment processing system and you’d only be able to pay at terminals that work with your specific bank.  Think paying with Amex is difficult now?  The whole thing would be a gigantic mess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For mobile money platforms however, that second scenario is the reality.  Most mobile money platforms are built around telecom operators, and suffer from two main issues: interoperability and complete financial services.  For consumers, this means having several phones, sim cards, and mobile wallets to have the flexibility that makes mobile payment practical.  For merchants, this means having multiple terminals to be able to accept payments from different mobile money providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the West, Visa and Mastercard solve these problems and have built a massive structure to ensure that they work well.  To use this system that works well, the merchant typically pays around 2-3% in fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s fascinating in developing countries, is that they skipped the entire dark ages of paying with cards and have gone straight to paying with phones.  However, there is no centralized structure for these payments and the entire thing is built on phone numbers, not card numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we talk about changing innovation in the banking sector, solutions like Apple are really just a fancier way to pay with a card.  The structure doesn’t change.  And in developed countries, it probably won’t for a very very very long time.  Everybody has a card, the networks are massive, and there’s no real need to change.  (Although…  Stay tuned because Bitcoin could kick ass)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In developing countries, this whole situation is extremely exciting because nobody knows how the system will develop.  There’s an unprecedented opportunity for a new banking structure that’s faster, more secure, and more advanced than what we have now.  As mobile money continues to expand in developing countries, it will be fascinating to see how these solutions deal with problems like interoperability, exchanges between countries, performance, security, and all the other problems that face traditional banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re curious, here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nRzTaWZ6ebs&quot;&gt;quick video&lt;/a&gt; of how card processors like Visa work. If you have 10 minutes, it’s kind of interesting.  TL;DR (TL;DW?) here’s more or less what happens when you swipe your card:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The terminal gathers some information on your card, the transaction, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;That information, along with the merchant’s ID and whatnot is sent to an acquirer (the merchant’s bank)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The acquirer sends the info along to the processor (Visa/Mastercard/etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The processor sends the info to your bank&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your bank checks if you have the money to spend and authorizes the transaction (hopefully)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your bank tells the processor that the transaction is approved&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The processor tells the acquirer that the transaction is approved&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And finally your card is approved and you get your stuff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh but wait.  The money still has to get from your bank to the acquiring bank and to the merchant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your bank keeps a cut of the money you just spent and sends the rest to the processor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The processor keeps a cut and sends the money to the acquirer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The acquirer keeps a cut and sends the rest to the merchant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://example.org/blog/posts/potential-for-mobile-money/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://example.org/blog/posts/potential-for-mobile-money/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Konza Tech City, Kenya</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Part of my job is researching things having to do with mobile money in Africa.  I’ll explain mobile money and why it’s important in another post, but future TL;DR, it’s important, you should care about it, and its potential is particularly huge in many African and Asian countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, the other day I stumbled upon some articles about Konza Tech City in Kenya.  Granted, the project started a few years ago, but I had never heard of it, I thought it was pretty cool, and I’m sharing it with you now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nairobi is one of the leading tech cities in Africa and is full of incubators, geeky people, and cool startups.  The Kenyan government decided to build the Konza Technology City nearby to capitalize on business outsourcing and IT things (more or less taken from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.konzacity.go.ke&quot;&gt;Konza City&lt;/a&gt; website).  Basically they’re building a brand new city from the ground up that will create hundreds of thousands of jobs and become the “Silicon Savannah” of Africa.  Oh and it’s also going to be sustainable,  livable, etc etc.  Mostly all good stuff (some criticism &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2015/jan/05/kenya-technology-entrepreneurs-konza-silicon-savannah&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big picture, Konza City speaks to the immense amount of innovation happening in Africa.  The most transformative new technology is born out of necessity.  A new way to turn on a lightbulb isn’t quite what you’d call necessity.  Providing financial services to billions of people using “dumb” phones they already own, is.  And it’s innovations like this that are happening in Africa today.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/toby_shapshak_you_don_t_need_an_app_for_that?language=en&quot;&gt;This Ted Talk&lt;/a&gt; sums it up pretty well.  Real innovation is happening in Africa because Africa is solving real problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://example.org/blog/posts/konzacity/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://example.org/blog/posts/konzacity/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Amsterdam</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;One of the best parts of living in Europe is how friggen close you are to some of the coolest cities in the world.  Last weekend I went to Amsterdam to visit a friend and spend a few days riding bicycles, listening to music, and drinking coffee.  Casual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you notice when you get out of the train station is the ridiculous amount of bikes.  It’s the most convenient way to get around town, and everybody does it.  I rented a bike for a few days, and apart from almost crashing a couple times, it was fantastic.  Amsterdam is one of the prettiest cities I’ve ever been to and riding down cobblestone streets next to the canals and accross bridges feels like you’re in a movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another cool thing about all these European cities is the amount of ridiculously famous art in all the museums.  Opting to avoid the 2 hour wait to get into Ann Frank’s house, I visited the Rijksmuseum.  I enjoy going to museums every now and then, and it’s always kind of cool to see things you recognize from old textbooks.  The Rijksmuseum is home to some well known stuff from Vermeer and Rembrandt, and just the building alone is impressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elephant in the room.  Coffeeshops.  Yes, I went to one.  Duh.  But honestly, it wasn’t all that exciting or anything.  Weed in Amsterdam is more for the older generation and tourists.  A few years ago they experimented with not allowing foreigners to buy weed at all.  In some cities I’m pretty sure coffeeshops can only sell to residents.  However, after they realized the catastrophic effect it would have on tourism, you can pretty much buy weed anywhere in the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, my weekend in Amsterdam was awesome and I want to go back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://example.org/blog/posts/Amsterdam/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://example.org/blog/posts/Amsterdam/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>What I'm doing here (in Paris for the summer)</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I started my job here about 3 weeks ago now at a small fintech company called Tagattitude.  It’s great, and what the company does is very interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are over 2 billion people in the world without access to financial services.  This means they can’t save for the future, take out a loan, send money, … - all the services many of us take for granted.  Of these 2 billion, over a billion have phones.  In some of the poorest parts of the world, mobile penetration has surpassed 90% of the population, giving these populations the only tools they need to access financial services that are just as advanced as those found in the western world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s where mobile money comes in.  It is extremely expensive for banks to build new branches in remote areas, especially given limited infrastructure and resources.  However, by turning mobile phones into payment devices, where your phone number becomes your account number, banks are starting to reach areas left underserved by the traditional banking system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company I work for provides the platform for mobile financial service (MFS) providers.  If you just can’t help yourself and want to learn more about what this entails, checkout the website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tagpay.fr&quot;&gt;tagpay.fr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this all matters because financial inclusion is paramount to the development of these areas.  Helping mobile money providers reach more people for fractions of the cost is a step towards bringing these parts of the world out of poverty.  With more money in banks, resource mobilization helps develops the area.  With quick and easy transfers, more people have access to loans, and microcredit.  They can develop a credit history, and have a safe place to save money for the future.  Mobile money also reduces the volume of cash in the system, helping workers get paid on time, improving security, and saving the billions spent today dealing with the logistics of transporting, distributing and securing cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the little experience I have, I’ve learned that for me, one of the most important things when choosing a company is to find one that is doing something worth caring about.  That is definitely the case here at Tagattitude and I’m glad to be a part of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://example.org/blog/posts/what-im-doing-here/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://example.org/blog/posts/what-im-doing-here/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>2 Weeks Back in the Western World</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;My semester in Dakar ended about two weeks ago, and now I’m in Paris until the end of July.  Being back has given me some time to think about my time in Senegal and the most important things I’ll take away from my three and a half months there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two very important aspects about Senegal I’ll miss, and I think we can all learn from here in the western world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is the strength of the community. From interactions with taxi drivers, to merchants, to waiters, to students, there’s a sense that everybody will take care of each other.  Senegal is one of the least touched countries by famines in the area because of people’s willingness to help other in times of need.  Families are large and everybody helps if a member needs help.  And families aren’t just blood related.  Close family friends and members of the community are also considered a part of the family.  So much so that I had friends who had aunts and uncles with whom they weren’t sure how they were related.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking down the street, you talk to people and say hi to all the familiar faces you cross.  When someone tried to rob a student on our trip, the entire neighborhood was asking her if she was ok for weeks.  Even the people she had never talked to.  People look out for each other and there’s a sort of connection you feel towards others in your community and neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second is how well the Senegalese separate money from happiness.  In a country where the majority lives with about $2 a day, I met so many more kind, relaxed, and genuinely happy people than anywhere else in the world.  And it’s not just a happiness you feel when talking to people, its something you feel walking down the street.  It’s a general feeling in the air where people are content with what they have, and happy to be alive.  Things move slowly and once you adjust to the general noise and chaos of the city, the vibe is actually very relaxed.  People don’t worry about money and wealth, and I think as a result, are happier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this second aspect about separating happiness from wealth stems from the first.  People’s happiness doesn’t come from the things they own, or even the things they do.  Instead it comes from those around them - from their community, their friends and their family.  And so after a couple weeks back in a country where people keep to themselves and walk down the streets with two headphones in staring at their feet, these are the two things I’ll miss most about Senegal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided not to import my senegal blog over to this one.  If you’re interested, the whole things over at &lt;a href=&quot;http://reidsata.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;rsata.blogspot.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://example.org/blog/posts/2-weeks-in-the-western-world/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://example.org/blog/posts/2-weeks-in-the-western-world/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Dinah Dodds Endowment Fund Grant Request</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This is the grant request submitted to the Dinah Dodds Endowment Fund. It received the maximum grant amount of $2,000, and the project is currently underway. The money is going to fund research on sustainable oyster farming and mangrove protection in Sokone, Senegal. The funds will also help develop these practices in the area, providing equipment to increase sustainable methods of oyster farming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://example.org/writing/posts/DD/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://example.org/writing/posts/DD/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Global Research and Advocacy Group</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Global Research and Advocacy Group (GRAG) is an NGO based in Dakar, Senegal that conducts quality research on various issues including reproductive health, family planning, education, and gender related norms. GRAG’s team comes from all around the world, and works to improve program initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;things-i-did&quot;&gt;Things I did&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Translate research and analysis from French to English and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prepared presentations for the government of Ghana and Burkina Faso in both French and English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helped write and edit grant proposals to several funds, including the Helwett Foundation, and MEASURE Small Grant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helped prepare materials for conferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dates&quot;&gt;Dates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;January 2015 - April 2015&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://example.org/work/posts/GRAG/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://example.org/work/posts/GRAG/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Rubicon International</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Rubicon is an education consulting company based in Portland, OR. They write curriculum mapping software to help teachers and administrators collaborate, share curriculum, and keep track of everchanging standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;things-i-did&quot;&gt;Things I did&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researched and developed content marketing strategy to help increase traffic to the professional development site. The strategy helped double page views, and is being used to help chnage the image of the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prepared and gave a marketing demo to senior members of the company, simulating an on-site demonstration of the company software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worked on the deployment team to help prepare and maintain client sites. This included growing and maintaining a database of over 1,200 sets of national, state, and international education standards.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://example.org/work/posts/Rubicon/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://example.org/work/posts/Rubicon/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
