<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Reid Sata</title>
		<description>Some writing among other things.</description>
		<link>http://example.org</link>
		<atom:link href="http://example.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>What I'm doing here (in Paris for the summer)</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I started my job here about 3 weeks ago now at a small fintech company called Tagattitude.  It’s great, and what the company does is very interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are over 2 billion people in the world without access to financial services.  This means they can’t save for the future, take out a loan, send money, … - all the services many of us take for granted.  Of these 2 billion, over a billion have phones.  In some of the poorest parts of the world, mobile penetration has surpassed 90% of the population, giving these populations the only tools they need to access financial services that are just as advanced as those found in the western world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s where mobile money comes in.  It is extremely expensive for banks to build new branches in remote areas, especially given limited infrastructure and resources.  However, by turning mobile phones into payment devices, where your phone number becomes your account number, banks are starting to reach areas left underserved by the traditional banking system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company I work for provides the platform for mobile financial service (MFS) providers.  If you just can’t help yourself and want to learn more about what this entails, checkout the website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tagpay.fr&quot;&gt;tagpay.fr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this all matters because financial inclusion is paramount to the development of these areas.  Helping mobile money providers reach more people for fractions of the cost is a step towards bringing these parts of the world out of poverty.  With more money in banks, resource mobilization helps develops the area.  With quick and easy transfers, more people have access to loans, and microcredit.  They can develop a credit history, and have a safe place to save money for the future.  Mobile money also reduces the volume of cash in the system, helping workers get paid on time, improving security, and saving the billions spent today dealing with the logistics of transporting, distributing and securing cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the little experience I have, I’ve learned that for me, one of the most important things when choosing a company is to find one that is doing something worth caring about.  That is definitely the case here at Tagattitude and I’m glad to be a part of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://example.org/posts/what-im-doing-here/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://example.org/posts/what-im-doing-here/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>2 Weeks Back in the Western World</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;My semester in Dakar ended about two weeks ago, and now I’m in Paris until the end of July.  Being back has given me some time to think about my time in Senegal and the most important things I’ll take away from my three and a half months there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two very important aspects about Senegal I’ll miss, and I think we can all learn from here in the western world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is the strength of the community. From interactions with taxi drivers, to merchants, to waiters, to students, there’s a sense that everybody will take care of each other.  Senegal is one of the least touched countries by famines in the area because of people’s willingness to help other in times of need.  Families are large and everybody helps if a member needs help.  And families aren’t just blood related.  Close family friends and members of the community are also considered a part of the family.  So much so that I had friends who had aunts and uncles with whom they weren’t sure how they were related.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking down the street, you talk to people and say hi to all the familiar faces you cross.  When someone tried to rob a student on our trip, the entire neighborhood was asking her if she was ok for weeks.  Even the people she had never talked to.  People look out for each other and there’s a sort of connection you feel towards others in your community and neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second is how well the Senegalese separate money from happiness.  In a country where the majority lives with about $2 a day, I met so many more kind, relaxed, and genuinely happy people than anywhere else in the world.  And it’s not just a happiness you feel when talking to people, its something you feel walking down the street.  It’s a general feeling in the air where people are content with what they have, and happy to be alive.  Things move slowly and once you adjust to the general noise and chaos of the city, the vibe is actually very relaxed.  People don’t worry about money and wealth, and I think as a result, are happier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this second aspect about separating happiness from wealth stems from the first.  People’s happiness doesn’t come from the things they own, or even the things they do.  Instead it comes from those around them - from their community, their friends and their family.  And so after a couple weeks back in a country where people keep to themselves and walk down the streets with two headphones in staring at their feet, these are the two things I’ll miss most about Senegal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided not to import my senegal blog over to this one.  If you’re interested, the whole things over at &lt;a href=&quot;http://reidsata.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;rsata.blogspot.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://example.org/posts/2-weeks-in-the-western-world/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://example.org/posts/2-weeks-in-the-western-world/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Dinah Dodds Endowment Fund Grant Request</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This is the grant request submitted to the Dinah Dodds Endowment Fund. It received the maximum grant amount of $2,000, and the project is currently underway. The money is going to fund research on sustainable oyster farming and mangrove protection in Sokone, Senegal. The funds will also help develop these practices in the area, providing equipment to increase sustainable methods of oyster farming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://example.org/posts/DD/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://example.org/posts/DD/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Global Research and Advocacy Group</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Global Research and Advocacy Group (GRAG) is an NGO based in Dakar, Senegal that conducts quality research on various issues including reproductive health, family planning, education, and gender related norms. GRAG’s team comes from all around the world, and works to improve program initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;things-i-did&quot;&gt;Things I did&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Translate research and analysis from French to English and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prepared presentations for the government of Ghana and Burkina Faso in both French and English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helped write and edit grant proposals to several funds, including the Helwett Foundation, and MEASURE Small Grant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helped prepare materials for conferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dates&quot;&gt;Dates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;January 2015 - April 2015&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://example.org/posts/GRAG/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://example.org/posts/GRAG/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Rubicon International</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Rubicon is an education consulting company based in Portland, OR. They write curriculum mapping software to help teachers and administrators collaborate, share curriculum, and keep track of everchanging standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;things-i-did&quot;&gt;Things I did&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researched and developed content marketing strategy to help increase traffic to the professional development site. The strategy helped double page views, and is being used to help chnage the image of the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prepared and gave a marketing demo to senior members of the company, simulating an on-site demonstration of the company software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worked on the deployment team to help prepare and maintain client sites. This included growing and maintaining a database of over 1,200 sets of national, state, and international education standards.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://example.org/posts/Rubicon/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://example.org/posts/Rubicon/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Incubator and Launch Seed Fund</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I am currently part of Lewis &amp;amp; Clark’s Incubator and Launch Seed Fund. I am working on a project called PlanIt, helping people explore their surroundings, and organize their days. My team was one of six teams accepted into the incubator, and we received a secondary round of funds to further advance our idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dates&quot;&gt;Dates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;January 2014 - Present&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://example.org/posts/ILSeed/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://example.org/posts/ILSeed/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Effect of College Tuition on High School Graduation: The Impact of College Tuition Changes from 2005 to 2010</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A paper written for a political science research methods class using quantitative methods, and examining the relationship between college tuition and high school graduation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://example.org/posts/pols201/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://example.org/posts/pols201/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Tensoft, Inc.</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Tensoft is a semiconductor management and revenue recognition software company based in San Jose, CA. I worked there as a digital marketing intern, helping manage social media, maintain and update the website, grow the blog, create content, and edit videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dates&quot;&gt;Dates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May 2013 - May 2014&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://example.org/posts/Tensoft/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://example.org/posts/Tensoft/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Retention at Lewis & Clark College</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This is a paper written for a public policy class. Many students come to Lewis &amp;amp; Clark for the appeal of a small, tight knit community. However, many students are frustrated by the lack of engagement on campus. This policy brief focuses on how the administration can increase student engagement to help address the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://example.org/posts/PolicyBrief/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://example.org/posts/PolicyBrief/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Op Ed Adderall</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;More and more students and employees are using adderall and other drugs to boost grades and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://example.org/posts/Op-Ed/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://example.org/posts/Op-Ed/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
